what you're a go to experience is a free
Quid enim tibi liberum est ire ad usum
worldwide interactive broadcast from
passim a worldwide interactive
Ontario Canada we broadcast live every
Omnes enim vivunt iaci Canada Ontario
tuesday at seven p.m. eastern time get
post meridiem ad orientem Martis per septem dies ut
your questions in join the community
quod in civitas iungere rogationibus tuis
chat room at triple w category 5 TV or
V TV vel chat cubiculum at triplex genus Latin
email us at live and category 5 TV and
et ad vivere, et nostrum genus email V TV
now let's begin here's your host or I'll
nunc ego te nec exercitum tuum de primo hic,
be Ferguson welcome to episode number
plures esse res grata Tacitus
159 of category 5 technology TV it's
V TV suus 'genus technology de CLIX
just the two of us tonight just the two
iustus erat nos duo tantum in hac nocte duobus
of us John is off sick so we're fighting
nos erant 'Ioannes ideo non vigilat male pugnando
for camera time and I was just we were
sicut in camera et fui fuimus
just commenting about how much taller I
sicut commentario procerioris intellegi quantum de me
love but you know John's not here my
Ioannes autem diligunt te scio suus 'non hic mihi
chair is that much shorter well yeah we
breviori multo cathedra ut bene sit nobis yeah
plan it that way wait until I get you
ratio est, quia ita, donec expectantibus te
out on ice wait until I get you out on
et expectare donec in te et in gelu
the ice well then you'll look a lot
Ergo multo glaciem petetis
taller than me because I'll be laying
me tibi maius consignandum
down you know what's with the shirt well
et nosti quid sit bene cum shirt
you know what our Mike are you hitting
Scitis enim, quae nostra Mike percutis proximum
the mic with no no I don't think so oh
et non est absque me non puto microform O
he's kind of fumbling with the mic there
C. Et cum sit genus BALBUS
is being absorbed into the hockey jersey
In consectetuer ligula sit absorptus
have lost my little wind sock heavens
habere amisit meus ventus mediis soccus caelum
well you know the color thing here our
Bene scitis quod color est hic noster
technical guy John who's not here
Non est hic, Joannem, qui guy technica
tonight right right he's probably he's
suus 'verisimile est, et hac nocte rectum ius et
likely watching from home apparently he
vigilantes in domum suam ab verisimile non videtur,
didn't like the fact that i was wearing
ut non quod ego amictus fuit,
black last week so I figured I'll show
Ultima septimana et nigri instar Et ostendit mihi
him go east we have the elder scam you
vadat tecum orientalem habemus seniorem scam
have color I left my hockey gloves
quia color non reliquit me hockey caestus
outside my sticks in the car I'm ready
haeret foras meo paratus sum et in car
to go pretty much ready to play great
Parati fere ad magnas
playing tonight I am you're a madman
Ego tibi hac nocte ludere noxius
I am how do you do it Oh long days my
Ego sum, quid faciam tibi o longa dies mei
long days this from having teenagers
longa dies cedit eleifend
they you know you're kind of used to it
tu scis quod genus consueuerint ad eam
says one needs an outlet what do you do
Quid agis, inquit eget exitum
with that stuff like I said you got
surrexit sicut locutus sum vobis, ut cum supellectilem
teenagers so welcome to category 5 TV
genus sic V eleifend grata ad TV
159 is the episode number tonight and
CLIX sit hac nocte: et facto quod numerus
we've got some fun stuff in store for
Comperto enim quaedam amet supellectilem copia in
you we are going to be set in Eric up
Thomas autem non sumus ornatum
with his first-ever Twitter account and
cum prima, atque ob umquam Twitter
we're going to be walking you through
erant 'iens ut ambularet in vobis
how to set that up from front to back
a fronte ad tergum, ut quem ad modum
including the GNU image manipulation
inter quas GNU imaginem manipulation
program process of creating your very
processus of partum vestri progressio valde
own avatar so stick around for that also
et quoque quod inhaero circum se avatar
we've got nanodots to give away tonight
Comperto ad nanodots hac nocte auferetur
you remember a few weeks ago always
meministis ante paucos hebdomades semper
trying to show it to the couch I wasn't
ostendere conatur ad ea in toro non essem
actually I was trying to peek oh you're
O vere ego Peek vestri 'trying
trying to look at what what this stuff
Quid enim hoc intueri conatur supellectilem
is oh definitely what that camera shot
O certum est quod camera illa iecit
go I thought I ever shot is there yeah
et cogitavi ut semper exortum est yeah
there we go let's get there we go
non venimus illuc imus, lets '
nanodots we've got something to give
Comperto quod ad nanodots
away if you were watching episode number
Si numeri sunt vigilantes res auferetur
126 you know all about that look at he's
CXXVI scis omne quod non est intueri
already playing with this stuff it's
suus 'iam ludens cum haec supellectilem
addictive I don't know my love to play
Nescio addictive ludo in dilectione mea
with this Oh totally this looks like I
EGO is prorsus spectat sicut hoc O
broke something already don't eat them
fregit aliquo eat
can I take them out of the bag you can
possum accipere ab eis potes lapides sacculi
take them out of the bag for sure they
pro certo eas de sacculo
look kind of neat they're pretty cool
quaedam lepida es pulchellus frigus quaerere
super super powerful magnets I'm
Super auxilio machinarum magneticarum potentissimarum Super me
thinking we should set these on your
ratus posuit super eum
hard drive and see how just kind of spin
quomodo iustus genus nent ferreus coegi
them around couple times they thought
duo tempora circum cogitarent
it'd be fun you can you can show them to
vellem autem esse non potest ut possis amet
the camera here and I said like this it
et dixit ei sic camera est hic
is kind of fun oh I broke it you're not
Quis es tu confregisti ridiculi genus
even sure I'm not there every day there
Im 'non certus est etiam cotidie
we go you've made some kind of fancy
tu autem vade in aliquo genere phantasiae
thing I have oh you know I'm gonna be
Im 'agnus dei esse non sum ego novi aliquid vobis O
playing with these all call through the
Vocatum per omnia ludit
show tonight Hey nope doesn't work
Veni ostendam hac nocte nope non operatur
through the desk this could be fun so
per iocum et id pluteum
stick around for your chance to win a
forte vincere in vestri inhaero circum ad
pack of nanodots tonight and we've got
Comperto hac nocte, et fasciculum nanodots
two handful of those give away you've
quantum pugillus capere potest duobus illis youve 'distribuero in cibos pauperum
pretty much talked most ourselves focus
ipsi loquebatur multo plus satis focus
on playing with keisha but what else we
sed si quid aliud ludens cum in keisha
got going on well we've got you've got
Comperto got tam iens in te surrexit
some news coming up I'm sorry to
nuntium quidam venit usque ad me paenitet
distract you from from your toy filling
distract toy impletionem ex te
the big okay they're kind of fun they
qui bene haerent magnus genus ridiculi
really are so I'm going to scrunch it
Im 'vere non iens ut eam scrunch
into a nice little ball there okay
In eu est purus orbiculus
like that yeah you're such an addled
yeah, quae qualis es talem te esse stultus
I'll be like that okay but why don't I
Ego ero similis Quin purus
tell them what's coming up in news that
dices ad eos ut quid suus 'venio in nuntium
would be that would be the him coming up
eo quod non esset ascendentem
in the newsroom at Oregon said the virus
newsroom ad virum dixit ad Oregon
bulletin 2010 conference have voted to
bulletin MMX habere colloquium censuissent,
abolish Adobe's PDF standard hmm to help
Adobe solvere vexillum scriptor PDF hmm auxiliari
usher in the future the FAA is now
ducentibus roadable futurum nunc est
offering grants for space ports oh I
heu mihi quia spatium cm concedit offering
know you're gonna that's good and you
Vos scitis quod bonum amet, et
already have well I start been planning
Iam tum erat ut satus planning
her start notice base yeah okay I do too
initium eius notitiam faciunt etiam tibi bene basi yeah
look this because one was not enough hey
quia satis erat consectetur inspicere
maybe I know it better not there's one
Scio quod maybe suus 'melius non est alter
for each of us wow you know anyways we
quia uterque wow anyways non scitis
also will be able to get a grant for our
Item poterit donatio ut pro nobis
spaceport okay that's fantastic Google
spaceport okay ut 'fantastic Google
is resorting to old-school tactics to
qui se ad vetus-schola pugnae
make the internet faster image
ad imaginem interrete fac citius
compression the end planet clip so it
ita finis leo cogo clip
was stepping things up for online gamers
quæ erat usque in online venatus po
with new hovercrafts I love hover crafts
cum te amo tabernus hovercrafts nova artificia
Oh motorboats and a secure in-game voice
O vox motorboats et secure in-ludum
chat system I was down in Florida and
ratio chat, et fui usque in Florida
actually we ran over an alligator in a
cucurrit in nobis in actu et in alligator
hovercraft what fun it was just the
hovercraft quod fun iustus erat
wildest thing anyway that was that that
ultimus mentium est, ut usquam fuit, ut quae
was a little safer most random thing
tutius est parum plerique temere
that ever mentioned hovercraft so that
qui umquam mentionem, ut hovercraft
just renowned yeah well anyway you ought
clarum est utique oportet bene memini
to stick around for the latest news from
circuitu tardus ad nuntium ab inhaero
category 5 TV get really oughtta
V TV vere adepto genus oughtta
definitely no other alligators no
Certe nihil aliud alligators
alligators tonight welcome to everybody
alligators hac nocte salvete omnes
who's joining us in the chat room
Quis suus 'veniendo ad chat cubiculum
category five dot TV so great to see you
genus TV quinque dat tantam te videre
if you're watching the show on justin.tv
Si vos erant 'vigilo ad spectaculum justin.tv
through through our WMS feed wherever
in qua per nostram WMS pascere
you are hop on over to our website
quae salit super site transfugit
category 5 TV and you'll see the live
V genus TV quod video te vivere
chat room right on our homepage if
Si recta pagina nostra chat
you're here during the live show but
hic autem ostendit per te vivere
otherwise the the chat room is always
aliter enim semper in chat cubiculum
available if you click on the
si praesto per click
interactive nu on our website or if
Num si nostro loco Interactive
you've got an IRC client you can you can
nunc demum istaec nata est clientis IRC potes, potes
connect into irc.freenode.net and then
et tunc coniungere in irc.freenode.net
you'll be
eris
to join us in our chat room which is
Visne nos comitari in chat cubiculum quod est,
category 5 i'm going for a hovercraft
Im 'iens pro V genus hovercraft
ride with job he said he has one he's
ipse est qui habet equitare cum autem Job dixit:
taking me up does he really oh boy John
ne me re vera ille puer o Ioannes
I haven't hung Huynh planet calypso
Non Huynh planeta pendente Calypso
probably oh I'm guessing so oh god how
O utinam Deus ita Im 'coniciens accidisse quam verisimile
we miss ya I haven't seen you in in game
Desidero enim videre vos non ya venatus
for a while so we're gonna be we're
sic erant 'agnus dei esse a dum sumus
gonna be taking a look at that another
Vide alium accipiens amet
day for sure indeed it is a few a new
sane paucos dies novum quidem
viewers under a strong oh yeah yeah yeah
O Yeah memini memini a Vergilio visorum
there's a logic from Hereford hey blah
illic 'a ratione de Hereford' heus non mauris non mauris
ok nice to have you here and foxton
nice quod Foxton 'ok ut et hic
Hayes also from the knee thing hey
Sepe etiam aliquid de genu heus
foxton Hayes and JV SCC from that tejas
J. Hayes, SC atque Foxton 'est inde Tejas
USA or maybe it's Texas and whoever
Vel maybe suus 'Texas et qui USA
transcribed this head trouble with thee
transcripsit caput tribulationis tecum
what do you saying well the copywriter
Bene ergo quid dicis de copywriter
te doing the copywriting is there a town
Te enim facientes Copywriting oppidum
called tejas ortega's te Jas hmm there
Tejas ortega dicitur Iac te hmm est scriptor
is maybe in its in Texas oh well we're
O bene maybe is in Texas sumus
all going to thats writ Aegis or
scripsit ad universos thatõs vel Aegis
somebody should tell me it's great to
Praesent magna quis diceret
have it here ah Texas they act Taeyang
Ecce hic habes agunt taeyang California
Taeyang tell ya how do you pronounce
Puer taeyang dicam et quid loquar
that in Spanish Greg is mentioning that
memoriam facientes in is, quae Hispanica Greg
that may be Spanish for Texas okay well
quod tam bene ut Hispanica ad Texas
it is it's great to have new viewers
suus 'magnum esse ad novum viewers
joining us this week please do join our
Hoc septimana noster nobis placet obsecro ut copulare
website category 5 TV it's free service
V TV suus 'liberum servitium genus website
and you can subscribe there become a
illic et facti sunt in Potest subscribe
registered viewer and that gives you
profiteretur qui dat inspectoris
some additional bonus features and also
et etiam features aliqua additional bonus
you can follow us on twitter twitter.com
potes sequi twitter.com Twitter
/ robbie Ferguson that's me and that
/ Quod est a me et robbie Tacitus
will be your chance to to get the inside
erit vester forte ad ad interiorem
scoop on what's coming up from category
numquid abscondere ex quo venio suus 'genus
five this week we had lots of exciting
Hoc septimana quinque habebat lots of excitando
stuff going on on Twitter as our green
materia viridi geritur ut Twitter
screen arrived and I'm just going to
et pervenit screen Im 'iustus iens
leave it at that but if you follow us on
sequitur quod si nobis permittimus
Twitter you'd know more
Twitter plura scire velis
well twitter.com / Robbie Ferguson where
tum twitter.com / Robbie ubi Tacitus
I also posted some video demonstrations
Ego missae etiam quosdam video demonstrationes
hi saw a little bit of that you did I
Hi viderunt paulum fecit ut ex me
did good stuff good stuff I wanted to I
nonne bonum supellectilem bona Volui ego supellectilem
was gonna just wear my green shirt
sicut agnus dei gerunt in viridi shirt meum
tonight so I could disappear but that'll
hac nocte ut non evanescet illud et si tibi placet
be great yeah I'm thinking that you know
yeah magna cogito, ut scitis
that will teleport or so I'm just like
Ianuae Magicae, quod non est simile sum,
wear a green shirt need to see a head
gerunt in viridi shirt a capite ad opus
floating around whatever works so and
tristique ac quibuscumque operibus
it's all thanks to telus dreams Wirecast
gratias actum telus somnium vidisse Wirecast
it's a brilliant application make sure
fac applicationem emicuit
you check it out that's what we use to
quid eum quaeras qui usi
broadcast the show but it provides live
Vivamus iaci spectaculum praebet, sed eam
green screen chroma key technology so we
viridi screen chroma technology sic clavem
can do multi-layered chrome wall we
Nunc autem multi facere Contact murum
could have alligators in the back or not
non potuit tergo Alligators
but we could we could but we won't you
Nos autem non in te, sed non poterat, sed non poterat
might okay so you got some questions
Veni autem ut esset aliqua
questions from people in the chat room
Quaestiones de populo in chat cubiculum
if you've got any for us make sure you
Si habes quis te fac nobis
say Robbie F or Eric Kidd and that will
Robbie F seu voluntatis et Kidd dicit Eric
come to our attention it's pronounced
dirigatur proferuntur eam venire
tejas thank you ok there what would have
quid enim est ok Tejas gratias ago tibi,
been my guess but it is not oh
O mea coniectura est, sed non
definitely would have been oh i thought
O certus putatur fuisse
you said i needed ironing so i wouldn't
et quia opus ei non ironing ego dixi vobis
show all the wrinkles but the the antics
sed in omnibus motibus ostendit obscenam rugis arat
that happen in the chat room mark are
nota sunt contigerunt in chat
you poking fun at the the ironing at the
et ironing ad te ridere
irony yeah I really you know relaxing oh
O vere dico vobis quia ruptis disciplinae vinculis locutus yeah
I'm just I'm just kind of hint in there
Ego sum, ego iustus non est in genere innuere
that we've got some exciting stuff
Comperto quod quaedam excitando supellectilem
coming up not today but season 4 we've
hodie venio, sed non in tempore non habes IV
got some really cool things around the
surrexit autem aliquid realiter frigus circa omnia
bend whew just kind of let that soak in
Eu sit inclinatio quaedam iusta macerentur
for just a minute because those of you
nam mox minutam quia illa de vobis
who know what what that's capable of
quod id quod potest scientibus
it's exciting stuff so questions we must
Itaque illud quaestionum debemus excitando supellectilem
have some questions just right off the
habent aliquam off Quaestiones iustum
bat well let's go we just had a 10
sicut vespertilio bene nobis erat X abeamus
minute introduction to the show talking
minute introductio ad spectaculum loquentes
about your hockey jersey and hey and
heus te et circa hockey et Jersey
silliness to see my other show Gators
spectaculum videre alios ineptiis meis Gators
and things so we really gotta move on
et vere sic moventur Redditus
that's as bad as the weather mm-hmm hey
id quod malum est tempestas mm-heus hmm
we could do the weather no I saw how
et vidi quam tempestas non potuimus
it's done no here we go okay I'm
Nunc factum est ut suus 'okay sum nihil
purposefully slouching just so you know
ita ex proposito Slouching scitis
that's
quod ut '
I see your sake yeah somebody wants
Quis non videre velit propter yeah
let's see hmmm that's thanks camel oh we
Scriptum est enim camelum O videamus nos gratias ago
like long as this fine okay well Phillip
Hoc denique modo tam bene sicut Phillip
greagle hey Phillip is he was thinking
Nullam est Philippus ratus greagle
of purchasing his first mass
primum ad mercandi
particularly from Buffalo technology
Lorem maxime Buffalo
linkstation mini one terabyte this Nass
Hoc unum mihi linkstation terabyte Nass
is raid 1 and raid 0 compatible i
et accinctus proeliabitur ante hoc tempus brumae, I 0 I. compatible
personally know very little about raid
habiturum scio parum de
and I learned what I do know from from
et norunt ex te didici, quid de
Robbie Ferguson no no from wikipedia i
Robbie nec Tacitus nec a varius id i
decided to were one in the same now he
eodem modo constituit in esse
decided it would probably not care for
quia verisimile non curo esset intelligens haec Appianensis,
redundancy so i believe that we'll go
addita, sic ego credo tibi ut vadas
raid 0 okay however here's my question I
hic tamen suus 'okay sum 0 expeditionem eundum hercle
understand that raid 0 helps the overall
Intelligo populandum ducebant 0 adjuvat altiore
performance of readwrite access correct
recto accessum in perficientur readwrite
but does raid 0 increase the chances of
sed tamen crescere casus 0 accinctus proeliabitur
disk failure if so by how much on
si peccatum in quantum orbis
average would raid 0 decrease the life
Mediocris vita essent pauci numero accinctus proeliabitur ante 0
of the disks I have this belief only
Ego hanc opinionem tantum de disks
because of this statement from Wikipedia
propter haec dicitur ab Vicipaedia
any disk failure destroys the array and
orbis ordinata et destruit aliquem defectum,
the likelihood of failure increases with
crescit elit augue
more disks in the array at a minimum
magis in disks ordinata ad minimum
catastrophic data loss is twice as
alterum casus funestissimi origo notitia est quod damnum
likely compared to single drives without
Verisimile non comparari unum agit,
raid yeah so we carry out this there's
hoc est ut memini incursiones facerent
no yeah that's okay he also has another
Quod ut 'non bene se habet aliam yeah
thought okay what if I initially run
putavit, si bene quid currunt initio
raid 0 and then let's say a few years
0 accinctus proeliabitur ante paucos annos et tunc lets 'narro
down the road I started getting
Sed et in via EGO coepi questus
concerned of the possible failures of
quorum interest ad fieri potest ex defectis
one of the drives would it be possible
quis foret possibile agitet
to connect another one terabyte your
ad coniungere unum alteri terabyte tuum
greater external hard drive using the
ferreus coegi per externa maior est
USB 2.0 on this nass and change the raid
USB 2.0 huius populationis Tarquiniensium fuit mutare et NASS
0 to raid 1 and back up all of the
0 I, quantae ad incursiones tergum sursum et in omnes
initial one terabyte of files on the end
terabyte ab uno fine ad initial files
asked to the new external thank you
interrogavit autem externum novae gratias ago tibi,
Phillip Austin text you hey fellow Tejas
Phillip Austin illud heus tu conservis Tejas
oh alright big long question I'm going
oh licet magna quaestio Eo tempore
to try to summarize it sounds like
summa nituntur sonat
you're okay you've got a raid controller
bene obtinuit es tu quoniam infuderunt se moderatoris
raid being an array of multiple hard
agmine multiplicium durum esse praedatum
drives redundant array of inexpensive
drives nugationem adducunt autem vilia sunt ordinata
disks I think we can say it like that
Ego autem, sicut non possumus dicere disks
that's what yeah
Hoc illud est quod yeah
yeah could be wrong I've been wrong
Ego fui nefas esse malum yeah
before right but but lay terms it's it's
condiciones autem iuri suus eam manusque
multiple hard drives connected together
ferreus agitet multiplici connexae
to create one volume or one hard drive
vel creare unum volumen unum durum coegi
so your computer sees it as one drive so
quaesitum igitur tuum computatrum perspicit ita ut coegi
for a Windows user you would see that as
Fenestra user ad hoc quod te videre
like your C Drive even though it's three
etsi suus 'similis tui C tria Coegi
drives or two drives it still just shows
neque duas adhuc agit quod agit iustum ostendit
as one like a c drive on a Linux system
c Linux ratio ut in unum coegi
it would show up as a single mount point
ut ostendam in una parte esset Mount
so a raid 0 is this is a like a striped
et diffusi sunt alba sicut 0 hoc est,
i guess like just a like it stripes from
i coniecto ut iustus autem quasi flagellis caedi a
one drive to the next so you you're
deinde ut unus coegi in vestri '
essentially doubling your chance of
se invicem ductis in casu tuo
failure for every drive that you add for
adde quod omnis coegi ad defectum in
every drop because if you've got one
quia si una stilla obtinuit omnem te
drive you've got chance to fail because
quia coegi te surrexit casu deficere
the hard drive can fail right if you had
quin, si te ferreus coegi
a second drive in a raid 0 you've now
Secundum youve 'iam a coegi in expeditionem eundum 0
got two hard drives either one of those
duas ex alterutro ferreus agitet
drives could fail if drive to now fails
si non posset nunc agit Coegi
you also lose drive one because it's a
expellet vos perdiderit, quia illud
raid 0 and you lose the entire stripe
et amisso clavo toto accingetur 0
set if you add through you know if
set si scire, si per te adde
you've got three drives in a raid 0
nunc demum istaec nata agit tria sunt in expeditionem eundum 0
gives you more capacity you've got lots
nunc demum istaec nata lots magis facultatem dederit tibi
and lots of space it gives you three
dat spatium trium multorumque
times the throughput the speed
temporum celeritas Throughput
essentially not not quite that but then
Non igitur per se non est, sed ut satis
you have three times the likelihood of a
ter a augue
failure because you've got three hard
te propter defectum difficile got tres
drives with in that array if any one of
Quod si quis agmine agit
those drives fails so now you've got a
deficit illud agitet ut tu nunc possedi
one in three chance of failure or I
tres vel defectum in uno casu a me
guess more than that however you know
qui tamen plures scis quam coniecto
you know what I mean like you've tripled
tu scis quid sit, sicut te tripled
your chance of failure with three drives
cum forte tres ex vestri defectum foras
you've doubled it with to the more
duplicetur porro, cum ad te amplius
drives the more chance of failure with a
drives magis ex defectum casu cum
rate one on the other hand it's it's two
Unus ex duobus rate Contra illud quod suus '
drives it's a mirror set so you've got
Speculum profectus est ut suus 'got scelera delebit te
exactly two copies of all of your data
Praeterea duo exemplaria notitia prorsus omnes tuorum
at all times so if one drive fails you
ut si deficit coegi semper
take out the failed drive you put in a
eximito defecit in a coegi vos
replacement drive it rebuilds the array
postea coegi illud reaedificat eam quae ordinata
and you've got access to your data again
et iterum obvius ut vestri notitia obtinuit te
because it copied it from the non failed
quia ex hoc non defuit copied
drive the only way that you would lose
ne repellas modo amitteret
your data is if both drives failed so
Si vestri notitia est ut tum defecit foras
you've effectively cut your chances of
tu efficaciter interficiam te in casum ancipitis
failing your data losing your data in
Venere data indicia prae tuo
half of what it would be for a single
cuius una pars esset
drive so it's basically like the
sic suus 'basically ut eiciam
opposite a raid one you're taking if
qui accipit si quem irruisti Oppositum
you've got chances to fail a hard drive
nunc demum istaec nata contingit deficere a dura coegi
you're
tu
those chances in half with a red one if
media siquidem casum rubra
you go with a raid 0 you're doubling
cum saepius duplicaret vos repentina populatione coeptum 0 tibi
you're doubling your chances of losing
perditio tua casus es invicem ductis
your data that said if you're looking
Si vestri notitia quod dicitur quaeritis
for speed raid 0 is super fast but I
Super ieiunium celeritas in expeditionem eundum est, sed 0
wouldn't I wouldn't depend on it myself
Nolo ego non pendent
I wouldn't especially with the speed of
Nolo ego praesertim cum velocitate
disks and the speed of the SATA bus
in DIABOLUS bus disks et celeritatem
these days so fast that it's in most
Dies est maxime retinebantur
cases not going to be really necessary
casibus necesse est non iens ut realiter
but what you'd find is that you can set
nisi velis id quod possis invenire, qui constitutus est
up a computer with multiple drives in a
sursum multiple agitet in a computer est
raid 0 to get the speed but don't
ut autem celeritas 0 accinctus proeliabitur ante non
actually use that array to store your
etiam per se ordinata istos apparatus vestros
data just use that to run your
Iustus utor ut notitia ut vestri current,
applications have a mirror of that so
Speculum habere applications illius est
that you can restore it to a new set if
te potest restituere, si is, qui est a paro
it does fail because of the chances of
et non deficere propter casum ancipitis
failure but you were asking about
sed defectum de erant rogabat
setting using a USB 2.0 drive in order
profecta est usura coegi ut USB 2.0
to expand the array and that would be an
quod esset ordinatus ampliare
absolute no because the as I was saying
quia non est absoluta me dicens
the speed of drives these days the speed
velocitas velocitatem diebus agit
of the bus is super fast three gigabits
Tria enim eu luctus Gigabits
a second and and beyond that with with
secundo quod est extra
some of the newer SI ta controllers and
Si et recentiora et quidam e moderatoris
things with USB 2.0 you're looking at
quae cum USB 2.0 ad vos quaeritis
only 480 megabits per second so it's
Secundum ergo illud solum per CDLXXX megabits
super slow plus it's easy to saturate
Super tardum facilis plus saturatas
that bus so in other words you'd be
bus, quod in aliis verbis sic sit tibi velis
copying data over and it would stall and
et data esset praesepio et describendis
then you'll be caught and it would
captus esset Chrys
continue and so that would not work as a
ita ut non opus permanserit
as a production drive that would work
ut productio coegi ut non operatur
for storage only but you wouldn't make
sed hoc non solum pro repono
that a part of your operating system
quae pars tui operating ratio
raid set so I think this was brought to
Nuntiatur tanti uerius puto
you by the department of redundancy
Donec a redundantia
department the redundancy department
Donec dolor est nugatio
department of redundancy department okay
Donec purus dolor nugatio
any other comments in the chat room
commentarios in chat cubiculum de alio aliquo
about raid 0 vs raid 1 I would always if
nos erupimus I 0 De diruendis exercuisset semper, si non esset,
the way that I would like the way I run
ut vellem in via curro
my system I have a single hard drive in
ferreus coegi in unum systema mihi habeo
my computer okay it's a very small hard
parva suus 'a valde bene mihi computatrum difficile
drive I think it's a 120 gig hard drive
Puto autem quod suus 'ferreus coegi ut expellam CXX cisiis pervolavit
and all it has on it is my operating
et non est in illo est operating
system a couple of applications that i
ratio est quia duobus applications
use but all of the stuff that i work on
sed ut ego utor omnibus de effercio operatur est
all of my files are stored on the server
omnes thesauri mihi concedebatur in calculonis servi files
where I've got redundancy so the server
Ego got ibi nugatio ergo servo
is my data storage unit
notitia repono unitas est
but that's that's so that way if my hard
sed id quod est ut suus 'difficile viam, nisi mihi
drive fails I don't actually lose
coegi ratio non amittunt,
anything other than my operating system
operating ratio aliquid praeter me
and maybe the files that I was working
et opus quod maybe quod files
on that week if I didn't move them over
in septimana moventur ea ni
to the server at that point I'm kind of
Conticuere omnes intentique ora in me servo genus
sad why I don't have a raid in my
quare tristis non est diffusi sunt in me
blackberry Oh what happened I lost it
Obsecro quid ego perdidi rubus
what did you do teacher no I did not use
Quid hoc fecisti mihi non uti non magister
happiness didn't lose the blackberry
amiserunt beatitudinem rubus
lost all the day I just had a vision of
amissa omni die iustus Videbam in visione capitis
you with a clonezilla CD and a
et vos cum clonezilla CD
blackberry and I've dropped them both of
Ego rubi, et utrumque remitteret,
them which one should I throw at the
mitte me quo ad eos
cement floor exactly well it because I
caementa pavimento illud quod tam exacte
saw what you did to a CD and that's not
vidi quae tu, et non ad CD
normal so what did you do to your
normalis Quid hoc fecisti tuam
blackberry I don't really know I've had
Ego scio vere quia non habebant rubus
it for many years it has in fact
non habet autem multos annos in eo
skittered across the floor on many
per multos in area skittered
occasion never been a problem come it
rei causa numquam veniet
doesn't even come to life now when I
ne quidem hoc modo vita cum veniunt ad
take the battery put it back in oh dear
Vae pugna terga dedit accipiat
yeah it didn't get wet it did not get
yeah eius infectum est non tantum non pervenit
wet it's just drop and just and it was
suus 'iustus stillabunt et umidus est et iustus erat
only from a chair to the floor this time
nisi de sella pavimento usque ad tempus
now its head tumbles before but yeah but
nunc autem in conspectu eius caput cadat, sed yeah
just the way it hit yeah with the
Quemadmodum ledo eam cum yeah
blackberry does it it doesn't store all
et congregabo omnia quæ non facit rubus
your all your stuff on the sim card
Sim card tuam in omnem supellectilem tuam
doesn't not much is on the sim card just
Sim card est non multum iustus, non est ex
your phone number well the phone number
phone in phone numero quoque est numerus
database yeah what else all not even i'm
yeah database quid aliud quidem omnia non sum
not even the phone numbers just the
ne quidem in phone numeris iustus
number of my phone is all I'm store oh
Phone numerus est mihi copia me O
just a pretty much more information from
multum iustus a pulchellus de magis notitia
the provider so the actual data like all
provisor in ipsa notitia est similis in omnia,
your contacts ya know I a bunch of
Puer contactus vestri ego novi fasciculum
photos they're on a little memory card
haerent paululum memoria card imaginibus
that's fine but ok but mine you take
et denique quod suus 'ok sed vos sumo meum
photos about my address book my calendar
de photos inscriptio libri mea calendar
you have gone and he said you have that
quae abiit et locutus est tibi
I'm gonna probably miss a hockey game
Im 'agnus dei est verisimile deesset ludum hockey
with you yeah do you have access to that
ut aditus ad te tu yeah
stuff when you plot like plug in a
si autem insidiamini supellectilem sicut per obturaculum
blackberry through USB when a king live
USB per rubus cum rege vivere
I can't make yes you can and I yeah I
Etiam potest explicare non possum non et ego yeah
did have a backup on my laptop which
laptop quod hoc a me tergum
seemed to have a motherboard problem and
et videbatur habere problema motherboard
I haven't backed it up in a couple
Non backed eum in duobus
months I know I know okay but you've got
sed scio bene te novi mensibus EGO got
like a couple month line I guess I'm
EGO coniecto Im 'lineam duobus velut mensis
just it's almost unheard gonna be a
sicut fere inaudita suus 'agnus dei esse a
problem right anyway i'll probably get
Ego ibo ut verisimile problema ius usquam
over you allude normal i do it the exact
super te autem faciam opus diei in normalis Grotius
opposite direction I've got like I don't
Non amo habeo oppositum
use
usus
you've seen my cell phone it's just a
et vidi mea cell phone suus 'iustus
little sony ericsson just a flip phone
Sony Ericsson paulo phone flip iustus
like just the old style okay because it
ut bene sicut antiqui, quod
still works and i don't i don't really
non tamen operatur et ego operor ego facio non realiter
care i barely use it but for my calendar
sed ego curare uti vix mea calendar
i'm on basically like a cloud computing
Im 'basically tamquam in nubem computing
architecture with zimbra so all of my
architectura et de omnibus angustiis meis Zimbra
stuff is on zimbra collaborative sweet
in dulce supellectilem Zimbra collaborative
and then I synchronized to that so so
et quia ita est, ut non synchronized
any of my devices are synchronized to my
cogitationes meae in omni vita mea synchronised
calendar which is on a server which is
qui enim in fastis cui servo
accessible from any of my devices
inventis ulli pervia
through the internet and on the server
per interrete et concedebatur in calculonis servi
it has redundancy plus it's backed up
id est nugatio plus suus tergum sursum
nightly so it's like a completely
Sicut ergo tota nocte
different approach true but if I mean
Sin vero aliter intelligo
that you believe my advice I've the
qui credis quia commune aut inmundum ad consilium meum
guide yeah I'd never lose access to have
Yeah numquam aditum habere vellem guide
access to everything was on a bed server
ut obvius omnia super lectum server
so that wasn't problem but you know it's
ut problema, sed non scis illud
right haps gadget was student guru
iure esset discipulus advenit gadget Guru
thinks i should consider an android
Considerandum putat Android
that's kind of shocked and coming from
et ex hoc genere abhorrent
Jim I think that kind of cool and I
Jim genus puto quod et frigus
would love for you to get an android
would amo ut vos quod Android
because like I said I still got the old
quoniam sicut locutus sum senex Ego got
sony ericsson so if you need to replace
Sony Ericsson si vos postulo ut reponere
and get an android bring it in and we'll
atque Android an efficere in nobis et si tibi placet
we'll see what we can maybe in gadget
quod youll 'animadverto ut gadget est in maybe nos can
wisdom ought to send anyone if viewers
ut sapientia alicui visorum
are starting to send in androids then
Tum satus mittere Androids
send me one too well okay there there's
ibi enim mihi nimium bene illic
a connector for zimbra collaborative
a 'on COPULATOR ad Zimbra
sweet as I as I think about zimbra that
quam suavis est sicut cogitare de Zimbra
allows you to synchronize it to your
quod sino vos ut synchronize tuo
blackberry to your I'm sure that they've
Im 'certus ut vestri quod rubus non habent
you know it's not the technology it's me
Non enim scis illud technology me
it's mine it's just willing to take my
mea est suus 'iustus accipere volenti mihi
love line where you know it's I preach
ubi noverunt eam lineam amor est mihi praedicare
it people yeah it's worth saving it's
yeah ut populus suus 'suus' dignitas salvis
worth backing up hopefully there's
Utinam valet tergum sursum illic '
somebody watching right now it's got
vigilantes quis suus 'iam got
their black bear and I think in their
Ursus puto eos in
blackberry and they're thinking I
ipsi erant 'non cogitas quod rubus
haven't backed this up in a couple
Non est autem in duobus backed
months back it up tonight right now
Nunc ea nocte mensis tergum
while you're watching the show hey we
dum vos vigilo spectaculum heus nos
could take a slap shot with that credit
posse accipere a tunde iecit ad se fidem
hey I'm not gonna call my blackberry
heus Im 'non agnus BlackBerry meis invocabo
cruddy but we could take a slap shot
sed LUTULENTUS posse accipere a tunde iecit
with it on the show something yeah
illud spectaculum, cum res yeah
okay we'll take it to e-waste I bet it
desertae et purus Maecenas id tollemus filiam bet
recycled can we do this laptop first
REDIVIVUS laptop vis ut faciam hac prima
sure forget the green screen I can
certus quod oblivisci non possum viridi screen
advise and people cheering it knowing
et monere atque laudantium cognoscentem
okay brilliant no cheering what else we
bene feliciter eveniret, quae lux non aliud nobis
got well okay that's because we're 20
Bene quod suus 'got bene quoniam sumus XX
after we've got that we can fit another
Comperto quod fit post nos mutuo
question before the news okay well I'm
quaestione prius ad nuntium tam bene me
trying to rise not here to be able to
hic non quaerit oriri poterit
zoom in I love it but gem LexA hey hi
sed hi quia amo zoom in deliciis lapidis heus Lexa
Robbie I want to take my winxp partition
Robbie volo ut winxp meis partitione
and put it on a larger HD hard drive
maiorem HD imposuerunt ferreus coegi
perhaps I think you talked about that
Tu forsitan putas loquebatur de illo
some time ago you use in clonezilla oh
olim in uteris O clonezilla
yeah bring up your broken CD to hit if
yeah bring up tua CD rumpitur, si ei ledo
you've hit a sore spot here next we're
next hit a te valde macula hic sumus
going to get questions a blackberry back
'iens impetro tergum a BlackBerry interrogationes
having some internet problems lately so
problems ut nuper aliqui penitus habentem
I haven't been able to watch the show
Non potest esse in spectaculum
live PS Ubuntu 10.04 has not supported
PS vivunt iam non valet Ubuntu 10.04
the Radeon 200 series drivers so i will
regentibus Radeon CC in serie sic ego autem
have to switch my OS or stick with 9.10
switch ad me OS vel inhaero 9,10
what is another good linux OS to try
quid aliud uelle Linux OS
keep up the good work love the show hmm
ut sunt amor boni operis ostendunt hmm
got the Radeon 200 you can't get it work
surrexit autem non adepto ut opus CC Pentium
and I that's a shame of course like
Scilicet ut pudor et ut '
what's another good Linux I don't use
quid aliud bonum, non uti Linux
ati cards radeon cards I'm straight
MSI ATI Radeon pecto pecto Im rectum
nvidia because i love not having that
non enim quia amo NVIDIA
problem but one that I always liked was
sed unus forsit ut erat semper probaverunt
pc linux OS you can get the live CD and
OS Linux possis vivere ut PC ad CD,
give it a try i'll post a link in the in
experimentum in peius post vinculum in
the show notes for episode number 158
ostendunt notas res pro numero CLVIII
people tell you you know try fedora
dico vobis quaerunt homines Fedora
mandriva is trying i think but there's
Puto tamen illic 'non trying mandriva
some there's some concern there about
quidam de illic quidam de illic '
about the business side of things so but
sed de re tam latus
pulled the chat room on that one what
Unus ex chat cubiculum quod illa extraxerunt
what other operating systems you could
operating systems alia quae poterat vobis
try that or linux based and maybe some
Et secundum hoc experimentum, vel maybe de Linux
people here also have okay and jameson
et hic populus et bene tibi jameson
is letting me know that that a TI
ego intellegam tu quid sit illud, quod in ti
is actually a legacy card so that could
et quidem ita ut legatum card poterat
be a problem are you interested in
quaestio esse es interested in
updating your your graphic card then if
Si ergo card graphic adaequationis vestra tuum
it's an legacy means that it's one of
an quod legatum suus suus
those like really old cards that are not
ut qui vere senex, qui non cards
like that are not supported because not
quia sicut non sustinetur
because linux doesn't support it but
Linux, quod non sustineant, nisi
because its soul obsolete that that it
ut animam suam propter quod antiquatur
doesn't do the things that Linux is
non facitis quae est Linux
capable of and people are reiterating
populus revocat et capaces
that that's a really old card so and I'm
senex card est vere id quod suus 'sic et ego
not familiar with the ati line anymore
ultra lineam adiecit ATI
but i would say that would be a good
sed diceret quod esset bonum
start the first questions there sorry
paenitet enim incipit primo quaestionum
you had it up on your screen now kind of
Nunc illud tibi in velum quoddam
looking over your shoulder but you want
volo autem vos vultus super humero tuo
the back to do there was first course
Nempe istic prius terga
Jam Alexa yes I'm there it is there so
Im 'etiam ibi est, jam non ut Alexa
it was the extent of our union XP
quatenus unio fuit nostri XP
partition to a larger hard drive yeah
dura est partitio maius coegi yeah
clonezilla I find is really great and
EGO reperio is vere magnus et clonezilla
it's free I never actually got to use it
suus 'liberum esse numquam got utor suus
you tried yeah I recommend that when you
memini enim quando ego suadeo vobis temptare
burn it to CD that you you don't throw
adolebitque illud in CD quod non mittent
it at things clonezilla org pardon me
net ad ea veniam clonezilla
there is okay so you can get the CD you
est bene ut vos can adepto ad CD
go to the website oh where did I what
et quæ fecit, quo venias ad website
did I click on my mouse is acting kind
et ego click mus agens in genere meo,
of silly there we go okay download and
Ridiculum autem est nos eamus, et bene download
you'll see that there's there are a
youll 'animadverto ut illic' non es
couple of different versions we've got
Comperto duobus diversis versions
the stable debian-based and the
et secundum debian firmum est,
alternate is ubuntu based what you want
Alternis idem est secundum id quod volunt Ubuntu
to know is there's this helpful link
Hoc est utile est scire link Index
over here that says difference between
dicit hic distinctio
alternative one or something like that
aut sicut aliquid, quod aliter se
so the differences are the debian based
ut autem ipsae differentiae sunt secundum debian
does not contain non-free software the
non continet liberum software est non-
alternative clonezilla live CD is a boon
CD est aliud vivere clonezilla boon
to based and it does contain non-free
Ad secundum liberum et non continere non-
software so that includes things like
software ut includit rebus quasi
your firmwares and things like that that
firmwares tuum, et huiusmodi, quae
are not included on the standard stable
non includitur in vexillum firmum
version so I would usually go with the
plerumque sic ibis cum Vulgata
alt alternative version just because I'm
alt versionem tantum modo, quia ego sum
looking for the most functionality not
Non quaero maxime functionality
necessarily being
necessario esse
free as in open source so clonezilla
liberi et aperta fonte ita in clonezilla
lets you make a clone of your hard
lets vos facere tuae dura cDNA clone:
drives create images of your hard drives
partum of vestri ferreus agitet agit imaginibus
and if you find that that is not working
et si autem habes quod non opus est,
for you like that that would be my
Vis enim, ut mihi non esset,
starting place always what's I don't
incipiens semper locus suus quod ego facio
know some people in the chat room can
scire licet aliqui sunt in chat cubiculum
probably suggest some some alternative
probabiliter quidam aliquid aliud suadeant
let's see it's at the tip of my tongue
lets 'animadverto suus' a tip lingua mea
but I haven't used it in a while because
ego autem non sum, quia dum usus est in eo
clonezilla works really well rms
rmat rem bene operatur clonezilla
sam says Peugeot makes a killer backup
Renault Vel Satis Sam dicit fecerit interfectorem tergum
yeah oh the DD command on Linux if you
O Yeah DD si praeceptum Linux
want to do a direct and that does not
qui volunt facere recta, et non
stand for disc destroyer okay let's
sta in puncto s bene pervideo vastator
direct okay what can know I've got that
bene obtinuit quod Ego scio quid directum
name because if you if you're not
Si vestri 'non nominat, quia, si
careful with your commands it will
diligenter erit mandatis
overwrite every sector of your drive
Omnium ordinum rescribere mina tua
whoops yeah whoops but it's that's a
sed quod suus 'a ululatus yeah ululatus
terminal command that's not a clone cell
terminalibus mandatum, ut 'non est a cellula cDNA clone:
as well it's kind of like a GUI it's
tum est quasi quaedam est GUI
it's like that it's a menu system at
quod suus 'similis ut a menu ratio in
least it's not a GUI but you know what i
minus tamen suus 'non scis quod i GUI
mean it's it's a menu it's not terminal
sit suus 'suus' a 'non est terminus menu
based
secundum
I'm thinking Akron asst truly have a
Antiquariat Posoniensis cogito Im 'vere have a Asst
couple of those commercial do click it
click duobus qui ea faciunt commercial
for DD that works works for me Akron
DD enim qui operatur in me opera Antiquariat Posoniensis
asst true image is it is a good a good
bonum veri est bonum quod est imago Asst
cloning software if you're looking for a
cloning software si vos es vultus parumper
commercial solution and the reason that
et quod commercial solution
that I would say you know it's it's
tu scis quod diceret quod suus 'suus'
worth mentioning certainly is one that's
certe dignum est ut '
really really good but two is it is
re vera bonum est, sed revera non est duabus
fully GUI so it's Mouse driven it's it's
Sic suus plene GUI mus pulsus est scriptor
quite attractive and it does a lot of
et nimium speciosam non multum
stuff it's if I were to if I were going
Si igitur materia est si essent
for a free solution i would go
solution ad liberum i iturum
clonezilla if i were looking for a
i Si sunt vultus pro clonezilla
commercial solution i would look at the
i respice in commercial solution
akron s products and this is available
s products praesto est et akron
off of their website at akron escom just
ad eorum website iustus off akron escom
felt just like that and look through the
ut per lepram abundantius
different products that they have
alia products quod sunt non
because they do indeed have a number of
quia multi quidem
different products that that you might
quod fructus aliter poteras
be interested in if you're looking for
si quaeritis sit amet
you know like this disk director is a is
hoc est quod amo director orbis novi te
a good one as well so they've they've
ita quoque se habent bonum, quod est illis operum
got some cool products akron esscom not
surrexit, non aliqua frigus products akron esscom
a sponsor anything just as software that
et quod justum est software quia sponsor
I that I've used in the past and and do
Ego sum autem quod et in praeterita
it's it's nice to work with it's nice to
suus 'nice quod suus' suus 'nice opus
do network backups of your hard drive
quid network coegi tergum of vestri ferreus
and things like that so there's a couple
et ibi duas res ita
of options for you and certainly a few
haud pauca tibi bene
of them coming in on the chat room as
Curabitur eorum ingrediatur in cubiculo
well therefore you Jam Alexa is that
Jam tum igitur ut Alexa
does that help you out i hope that the
Spero ex hoc quod esse tibi
dough's point in the right direction
coxeruntque farinam est scriptor punctum in partem dextram
start with clonezilla that's the free
quod est liberum clonezilla incipere
software to get you going and then from
software ut et tu ex
there take a well there are some more
accipies quoque ibi quaedam sunt magis
free solutions being posted in the chat
Curabitur libero solutiones quae posted
logs so check out the chat logs for this
Lorem Curabitur ut omnia acta huius
episode 159 for anyone who's watching
quis suus 'quae spectant ad res CLIX
this half of the fact jam alexis joining
hac de re jam medium conjungens curat Alexis
us in the chat room so so that's cool
ita et nos in chat cubiculum quod est frigus
and just mentioning that that they
sicut commemoravit et in se
downloaded the akron asst trial this
ad iudicium hoc downloaded akron Asst
morning and that's that's a great
id est, et qui mane magna
application so i would stand by that and
sic ego non stabit et applicationem eo
it's certainly worth the fifty dollars
illud certe dignum et quinquaginta dollariis
that it cost to buy I mean for the end
quod sit finis tibi emere cost
you can use that as more than just a
Vos can utor quod magis est quam iustus
one-off copy from one hard drive
ferreus coegi off-unus ex uno exemplum
the next you can use that to image
altera, quae uti potes ad imaginem
incrementally your hard drive so you
incrementally vestri ferreus coegi ut vos
create one big image save it to your
nisi illud magnum imaginem tuam creare
network server if you have one save it
ipsum si quis cultor salvare
to your pogoplug even okay that's a good
etiam okay ut 'bonum tibi est ad Pogoplug
option for you and then every night you
nocte et bene tibi erit
have a nightly run that takes just the
capit iustus have ut currere nocturna
files that have changed and backs them
et terga vertit illos qui in files
up as well so then if you have a hard
Ergo si durus est tam
drive crash and you've got akron asst
tu agitare et in ruina obtinuit akron Asst
installed you can install it you know
installed quod vos can install scitis
put in a new hard drive get your
adepto vestri ferreus coegi in novum
computer back up and running and an
et computatrum currit retro et
image it back or if you can't get your
vel vos can adepto vestri tergum nec imaginem eius
computer running or you don't want to
cursus vel non computatrum volunt
reinstall the operating system just boot
restituo operating ratio iustus tabernus
from the akron s boot CD and copy back
s CD et effingo tergum tabernus ex akron
off of your pogoplug or off of your
off tui Pogoplug vel off tui
network device and your computers were
computers in vestri network fabrica
right back to where it was cool cool
unde placitum fuit frigus ad frigus
Craig's asking about what about using
Craig scriptor quaeritur de illis quae per circuitum
our sink which is kind of a different
sentina quaedam alia quae nobis
tool that's more of a backup solution
tool solution tergum, quod suus 'a magis
and I use that all the time with my
Ego utor mea, et qui sunt in omni tempore
pogoplug I love it and for those of you
et amare illa ex vobis quia ego Pogoplug
who haven't heard of the pogoplug you
et non audivimus de te Pogoplug
can check that out pogoplug com that's a
Ex hoc autem com can Pogoplug
network attached device that lets me
annexum ipsum dimittit me pessimas
back up my stuff through the internet it
tergum sursum per interrete et supellectilem meam?
was a off-site so but 135 really we've
off-site erat, sed ut nos Ive 'realiter CXXXV
done a lot of stuff you have a pogoplug
factum sit amet effercio Pogoplug
so even you can search our website for
sic et nostrum website vos potest ad quaerere
it if you if you're interested but our
Si vestri 'interested si autem nostra,
sink is great for that backing up file
Labellum tergum sursum lima ut magnum,
by file incrementally that kind of thing
res quaedam quae lima per incrementally
whereas kind of what Jam Alexis looking
Jam vero id genus spectare Alexi
for here is more of a direct disk to
hic enim est de recta orbis ut
disk image so that it's like a bootable
orbis ut suus 'imago quasi bootable
copy of the entire operating system not
exemplum totius operating ratio non
just files so a little bit different as
aliud quod iustus lima ut exigua
far as what that is so cool hope that
quid enim est quod auram spei
helps tamil x that's great to see it
Tamil x adjuvat ad illud quod est maximum
here in our chat room category 5 TV and
hic in chat cubiculum ac genus V TV
nice to have everybody joining us
bellum ut in omnibus nobis placet
tonight you ready to hit the news I
Vis hit in hac nocte nuntium ad me
think we should I think that would be
Puto fore puto
fantastic can we have some little news
aliquid parum possumus habere fantastic nuntium
music ya know from a category 5 TV news
ex musica cognoscere genus y V TV News
at the better spot in twenty ten
decem ad viginti meliore loco
conference last week a whopping ninety
colloquium tandem nonaginta et octo whopping
seven percent of hold security experts
ex septem percent hold securitatem experts
voted in favor of abolishing and bookies
abolendi et bookies per gratiam voted
PDF standard outright security experts
PDF malis securitatem vexillum experts
have been keeping an eye on Adobe's
sunt semper oculum super Adobe observatio est scriptor
products as of late due to the fact that
products ut nuper ex eo, quod
many hackers are shifting their focus to
pluribus focus in altum euectae sunt hackers es
vulnerable products such as PDF and
products et vulnerable ut PDF
flash which recently discovered exploits
quae nuper inventa res mico
of Adobe's proprietary formats allowing
Adobe est proprietary formats de permittens
malicious users to compromise your PC is
malicious vestri PC users ut sit compromise
becoming more and more clear the new
magis magisque patet novum
portable document format is required one
Portable Document Format requiritur unus est
that puts a much more solid focus on
quod puts focus in est solidum multo amplius
security in an effort to patch recent
securitatis in labore ad consequendum recens repeciare
exploits which are raising concern over
de iis quae gesta res per
the safety of the product adobe released
Adobe dimisit productum est salus
their latest version of adobe reader
tardus Adobe Lector versionem eorum
today one week ahead of schedule you
hodie una sabbatorum ahead of vestri schedule
know what I find is interesting is that
EGO reperio is interesting quid est, quod
with the adobe exploits it's not just
cum suus 'non iustus Adobe titulos inponimus
the pc anymore we're seeing more and
Et cum erant 'iam plus in PC
more that this is a way that attackers
quod ultra haec est autem ut populus stationis eorum
are able to get into the mac computer as
ut possis in computatrum quod Mac
well well and linux like I mean that's
ut sit tibi bene et optime quod linux
able to open up some pretty dangerous
aperire possunt aliqua pulchellus periculo
doors that's that's just kind of a
quod genus est illud valvas
scythe on but it's kind of an
sed in alicuius generis secato
interesting fact so I agree with that
quod interesting ut cum eo
let's get rid of PDF there you go well
lets vos non bene impetro rid of PDF
gone well the FAA or the Federal
abiit quoque cum FAA vel Federal
Aviation Administration which oversees
Aviation Administration qui oversees
and regulates all aspects of civil
et facies omnium civilium rectificet
aviation in the United States announced
in Civitatibus Foederatis Americae nuntiatum aviation
a grant program for projects related to
program for projects ad donationis involveret
the development and expansion of
quod progressioni atque dilatationi
commercial space transportation
spatium translationem commercial
infrastructure oh good so I can grow my
O bona infrastructure ut possit crescere me
spaceship collection you can do that
spaceship collectio potestis facere
good the first matching grants managed
bonum primo matching grants managed
by the FAS official of commercial space
FAS publica spatium in in commercial
transportation transportation I can say
translationem translationem possum dicere,
that word include the following projects
quia Verbum includit sequenti projects
New Mexico spaceport Authority for an
New Mexico pro an auctoritati spaceport
automated weather observation system
automated system tempestate observationis
Alaska aerospace for a rocket motor
Alaska eruca et aerospace motricium
storage facility the East Kern Airport
Cerno repono facilitas oriente Airport
district in Mojave California for an
regio in California est in Mojave
emergency response vehicle and the
subitis responsio ad vehiculo et confortatur
jacksonville airport authority in
in aeroportus auctoritate jacksonville
florida to develop a spaceport master
Florida ut develop a domino spaceport
plan the funding was made possible by a
funding in consilio factum esse a
new National Space policy unveiled
National revelata novum consilium Tractus
President Obama that focuses on
Praeses Obama qui focuses super
public-private partnerships for
Societates, in privato publicum
commercial space flight over government
commercial spatium fuga per regimen
operation of space exploration it's cool
operatio spatium est exploratio suus frigus
we did a news story a while back
nos fecit per nuntium fabulam aliquamdiu retro
actually before you started about a
ante vos coepi de actually
group of volunteers who were sending up
coetus uoluntariorum quos mittebat
a spaceship spaceship well a rocket and
spaceship spaceship, et etiam erucae
and it didn't happen well what happened
Bene factum et non factum
I missed us they had they had something
Adfui nobis habuerunt aliquid quod non
leak Oh as they were about to launch and
O quantum est de se rimis fatiscere atque launch
so they had to call it off it's probably
et vocavit eum ut suus 'forsit
a good gonna happen in June now oh but
At nunc amet accidere bono Iunius
that reminded me it's like well they
qui me fessum suus 'quoque similis illi
could have used funding to patch that
ut resarcio ut possit habere usus funding
leak and no there's funding but note and
rimis fatiscere atque illic 'sumptu, non autem nota et
now the funding is there but it's it's
nunc autem suus 'suus' non est funding
kind of a little late for them okay but
Bene autem quaedam paulo tardius eis
that's that's the story rather than
id quod historia est magis, quam
simply adding more capacity to the
facultatem ad simpliciter addendo
internet pipeline or adding new and
vel addere novam ac penitus pipeline
exciting cash features to your browser
excitando cash features ut vestri pasco
Google is thinking inside the box
Google cogitabat intra buxum
labeled 1997 and instead launching a new
et pro MCMXCVII intitulatum a launching
file format to decrease the size of
magnitudinem formae q.e. minoravit
images by about forty percent when
cum quadraginta sentio simulacra
compared to the JPEG format while
comparari cum in forma JPEG
maintaining the perceived quality the
servata tamen percipi qualis est
new format is called web p and is based
novus forma dicitur, et textus p fundatur
on the vp8 codec which Google open
in quo cod vp8 aperta Google
sourced in May imagine a web site
radix in May situ meditati
loading forty percent faster on any
quadraginta percent in omni citius loading
connection or being able to store forty
sive connexionem esse poterit servari quadraginta
percent mark photos on your digital
in digital signum photos percent
camera how about being able to email
quam de camera potest esse email
forty percent more images to family and
familiari et quadraginta sentio simulacra
friends in one email blast oh my
amicos heu mihi inspiratione una inscriptio
goodness fantastic you think okay these
Suspendisse purus bonitate haec tibi
things are all possible with web p you
omnia tibi possibilia sunt apud textus p
don't have my angle oh well you're not
O mihi tum te non angle non habent,
going to talk about family pictures okay
'iens loqui de familia bene imaginibus
perhaps the most exciting for developers
fortasse enim blandit tincidunt
is the addition of transparency support
Praeterea subsidium est perspicuitatis
because google has plans to add full
Vigilante Googles addere plena est consilia
support for transparency to web p the
ut subsidium textus p perspicuum est
size difference becomes even greater to
magnitudine et differentia maior
give you an idea of the implications at
pertinentes ad rationem dare
present web developers have to rely on
web developers nunc have ut fiduciam
the lossless PNG format in order to
PNG ut forma ad lossless
include RGB images in their websites
RGB includit imagines eorum websites
which contain transparency PNG files are
PNG continet perspicuum et quod files
quite large and the entry
maiores vestibulum
of transparency support the web P means
perspicuum est P modo textus support
taking a 620 kill a bit image down to
DCXX imago in paulum ad occidere taking
only 43 kilobits ah by its kilobyte
XLIII kilobits solum ah per megabyte
sorry it's a little me there oh okay
paenitet enim me paululum suus 'okay O
that means some websites could load up
ut in turpis non aliquam websites
to 14 hundred percent faster using web p
XIV ut usura textus p centum percent citius
that's substantial that that's quick you
quod est substantial quod vos velox quod
do enough web design to know that's
satis est scire Web
that's quick like taking a ping and
quod velox est ut ping et taking
taking it down to 43 kilobytes Wow
Curabitur ferens descendit XLIII chilioctetis
fantastic I sometimes create sites that
ego creo locis ut numquam fantastic
have lots of things because I love
quia amo have lots of rerum
transparencies and I don't love internet
transparencies et non penitus diligere
explorer you know you've made that
Vos scitis quod factum est rimor te
apparent sorry yes google has a long
apparent etiam contristati habet longam Google
uphill road ahead as they try to turn
ut trudi conantur uertere iter emetiendum
web p into a standard that is supported
p textus vexillum in illo facit
by web browsers across the board
a web pasco trans tabula
beginning with a future version of their
principio noto ex terminis futuris versionem eorum
Chrome web browser now what about all
Textus pasco quod Chrome autem de omni
the graphics software and stuff they're
et tu ad supellectilem ad graphics software
gonna ya ghous all across the board
agnus dei Agnus ghous omnia trans tabula
right yeah cameras digital camera can't
yeah digital camera dextra cameras potest
just do this overnight no no big deal ah
non non hoc modo magnus paciscor ah pernoctare
planet calypso and hovercrafts Oh planet
O planeta et Calypso planeta hovercrafts
clip what is that an alligator oh no no
tonde quod est non non venias ad alligator
no alligators plan eclipse a massive
alligators non vis ingens eclipsis
multiplayer online game based in the
in online lusoribus ludum fundatur
fictional entropia universe has launched
poetica entropia universum has launched
an update almost as huge as the planet
ingens prope ad an update sicut planetae
itself it wasn't long ago that mine dark
quia ipsa erat, non diu abhinc adversariis meis tenebris
the makers of planet calypso introduced
factores planeta Calypso introduced
land-based vehicles to the free online
liberum online fundatur vehicles in terra,
game but thanks to the latest update
gratias ago sed tardus ad ludum update
players can now get their hands on
ludio ludius can adepto iam in manibus eorum
hovercraft and motorboats to give them
et dare Hovercraft motorboats
the chance to explore the planet
forte in planeta ad explorandum
stunning scenery like never before fly
Suspendisse scaenarum, sicut numquam ante volant
safely over mobs of deadly alligators
terrore requiescet super adlecti alligators mortiferum
hunt creatures and get to where you're
et ibi te ad venari creaturae
going fast in addition to the exciting
praeter iret celeriter in excitando
update an integrated secure voice chat
an update integrated secure vox chat
system now allows you to speak with your
ratio autem concedit non loqui de tua
Calypso friends possibly eliminating the
Calypso, amici forsitan removeantur
need for the traditional mumbling sounds
opus enim sonitus traditional quasi balbutiens,
associated with the in-game characters
consociata cum in-ludum characters
to top it all off planet clips will also
Ad PP eam omnia off etiam planeta clips
now features social media and
et nunc features socialis instrumentis
Gration allowing your Twitter followers
Gration tuo permittens Twitter
or Facebook friends to know when you've
amici Facebook vel scire cum tu Ive '
won an event received a Hall of Fame or
eventu famam obtinuit aula accepi
global and more users who would like to
global users et qui would amo
enable social media integration can do
social integration potestis facere media enable
so by logging into the planet calypso
planetae per colligationem in Curte
its website download your FREE copy of
download: Millions of suum website
this incredible game at cat5 TV /
hoc incredibile sceleris CAT5 ludo in TV /
Calypso you've been told get the full
Ad Calypso, ut plenum esse te
stories at category five dot TV
ad apicem quinque historias TV genus
newsrooms really hunt category 5 TV news
newsrooms vere sectaris genus V TV News
room is brought to you by roy wa ash
Roy wa cinis pro vobis est
with contributions from gadget wisdom
per contributions ex sapientia gadget
guru god we got to do the name drops all
Guru nos got ut faciam Deus deponat omne nomen
the people who helped us out with the
Nos autem, qui ad auxilium populus cum
with the stories that converges solution
de fabulis, quae convergit solution
yeah and our community of viewers
yeah nostri et civitatis de viewers
absolutely of which there are many many
quae sunt omnino multis
characters there i can tell by the chat
non possum characters dicere ad chat
room and that when we say the community
et locus non est, cum dicimus civitatem
of viewers contributes to the newsroom
de viewers confert ad newsroom
what you can do is pop us an email at
apud nos an email quod possis facere pop
newsroom at category 5 TV anytime you
V tu aliquando TV ad genus newsroom
come across a story that that you think
occurrit illud tibi fabulam
is worth mentioning on the on the
Est digna est quod in
newsroom Eric could read that during the
Eric newsroom legere poterat, ut in
segment during the live show but also it
Vivamus sed etiam in parte ostendit esse
could make it on to the newsroom podcast
Missa ad eam posset Newsroom
as well a category 5 TV / newsroom
tum TV est genus V / newsroom
indeed which is audio only and if you
qui non audio quod certe, si
haven't subscribed to that yet you'd
nec tamen consentire subscripsit, quae velis
like to get your weekly tech news we
ut ad tuum nuntium non weekly tech
weed out all the boring stuff and give
Seminaria runcare atque omnem supellectilem amet
you nothing but the good stuff Louie
Tu nil nisi bonum supellectilem louie
category-five TV / newsroom and if I
Quinque-genus TV / et si newsroom
record it early enough in the morning I
et recordarentur satis mane mane me
have this deep news radio voice it works
hoc alta voce radio nuntium non operatur
really well for me maybe I should start
bene maybe EGO should satus mihi re vera
doing those well you've done one that
bonum autem facientes fecisti
was fun except hockey's conflicting with
Contra est fun nisi consectetuer
the the reading of the podcast that's
Mass in lectio ut '
terrible yeah cuz if you've got to go to
yeah terribilis cuz si te ire got
hockey after the show god that's when we
hockey post spectaculum Deus suus cum eo
record the news read straight so right
legit statim nuntium in iure et recordarentur
now unreal stick around we are going to
Nunc lignum unum ens circa nos facturus
be giving away some nanodots in just a
ut det auferet a justo aliquam in nanodots
little a little bit if I can get the
si paulum paulum huic dormienti abstulero coitum
camera working where's John when you
operari cum camera ubi Iohannes
need them oh there it is nanodots and if
O illis postulo si illic est: et nanodots
you'd like to win a set of nanodots you
tu velis vincere statuto nanodots
saw Eric playing with them earlier I
Eric ludens cum vidisset eos: mane apud me
will be playing with them later make
et postea cum illis faciam ludens
sure you check out episode number 1 156
certus vos reprehendo sicco I pluribus res CLVI
of category 5 TV
V genus in TV
where you'll find out how you can get
ubi youll 'reperio ut vos can adepto sicco
your hands on a set of those tonight oh
Quis autem nocte manus Statuto
I turned my mic off thank you my mic is
Et convertit me microform off gratias ago tibi microform est
still on sorry it's very blue right yeah
Yeah ius ipsum hyacintho adhuc _Hostes
I was I in your cough candies you want
Ego eram in CUPPEDIAE expuli tussim tibi
one I'm actually doing better this one
quis me uno potius quam meliora hunc
doing pretty good all right that was our
satis facere omnia quæ fuerunt
moment of silence as a yes had a little
Etiam ut paulo silentio
bit of blueberry juice it's probably
Herpothamnus sucus aliquantulus of suus 'verisimile
good for me I want to learn or learn you
sive bonum est mihi cognoscere te volo discere:
you're gonna learn we rose up Larry I
Surrexerunt autem discite Larry et tu amet
want to learn you how to how to set up a
quam vobis volo discere quam ut rationem
Twitter account because you know it's
Quia nesciunt Twitter propter illud
always amazing to me when someone says I
semper admirari, cum aliquis dixit ad me dixi
never used Twitter oh I think I set up
O umquam Twitter usus Ego autem constitutus sum
an account about I don't know a year ago
Nescio enim rationem circa annos abhinc
but I never done anything with it how
sed non est aliquid quod
tweeted is no that was bad it was best
id est optimum Tweeted malum
terrible it was terrible twitter com
twitter com terribilis horrendum,
you've heard of it absolutely a lot of
omnino non audivi praeter hodie multum
people avoid it because they're not sure
ne sit populus es non certus quod
you know what is it what what good is it
tu scis quod quid est, quod bonum est,
what value is it and and what's the
et valorem quod est et quo est
purpose in it and then of course there's
Id profecto illud ibi
those of us who avoid it just because of
modo ne quis ex iis
the fact that there are spammers just
spammers quod illic es iustus
like any service you can expect to
quale ministerium Expectat
receive some spam to some degree but
Sed aliquam aliquam spam
once you've got a fairly good list of
Quondam youve 'got satis bona est album
people that you're following the spam
quia tu populo in his spam
actually tends to kind of fall into the
est genus in quod etiam tendit
mix and there's not a whole lot about it
misce et inde non multus
because twitter does a good job of
quod non a BENE de molestie egestas
kicking out those people that are trying
ex his populus es trying ut kicking
to spam you but i find you know I follow
spam ut inveniam te, sed nosti me sequere
about 400 people and so that the amount
et quantum est hominum circa CD
of spam that I get within that list of
ut in eo quod est album of spam
messages that I receive the interesting
percipite verba mea interest
thing about twitter is that you're
aliquid de te, ut est egestas
limited to 140 characters unless you're
nisi vestri 'limited to CXL characteribus
a jamison who who provides me a link to
et Jamison qui providet, qui mecum est vinculum
read more oh hey but essentially you're
read more heu heu per se, sed tu
limited to 140 characters so it's like a
sic suus 'limited to characters quasi CXL
quick way to find out what's going on
a velox via ut sicco quis suus 'iens
with my friends what's going on 140
quod suus 'iens die cum amicis meis epularer CXL
characters was enough to kill off Gordon
Occide omnes characteres erat satis Cicero
Lightfoot in a tweet that's true
Hefele 'verum, ut in Tweet
actually made national news
actually nuntium in nationalibus
yeah he was a lot of people have been
yeah erat multus of populus esse
through that he was reading it in the
per quae erat legis in ea
paper what the heck yeah wait a minute
Quid heck charta yeah manere unus minutam
I'm pretty sure I'm allina that's
Im 'pulchellus certus sum quod allina
happened to a lot of people I had bill
Et factum est multus of populus qui legis
cosby's had to deal with that four times
Cum eo enim in quadruplo Cosby
now I gets ridiculous but actually gourd
ridiculum est, sed accipit nunc cucurbita
pointed out though that they started
quamquam ostendit quod inceperunt
playing as so much fun the radio a lot
quod fun ludo tam multum in radio
that's brilliant right yeah so a Twitter
quod egregie yeah dextris et a MySpace
you know is a way to get kind of the the
scis enim quomodo non est in genere sunt ut
lowdown on what's going on on there are
quid agatur in Gemini sunt
some really cool integrations ways that
integrationibus aliquid realiter frigus vias illius
you can use it for me I've got it set up
vos can utor eo ut me Reperi extruxerat
so that any time that we post a news
et quod post quando per nuntium
article in the newsroom for example if
Si exempli gratia in articulum newsroom
you're following me you'll actually get
haec tu mihi, youll 'adepto actually
the the first line of that article as a
ut dictum est in primo
tweet so you'll know okay well then
ut bene nostis, bene et youll 'Recipes
there's an interesting tweet about you
illic 'an interesting Tweet vobis
know about planet calypso or about
de planeta vel scire circuitum Calypso
something else that's going on in
aliud aliquid quod suus 'iens in
technology that week and then you can
et quia non potes technology sabbati
follow the link if you like and read the
Si velis legere et sequentur nexum
story or you can find out what's going
quod suus 'iens vel vos can reperio fabulam de
on you can find out if you're following
Si vos can reperio his et in te
us when we got the green screen for
in viridi screen pro nobis quando surrexit
example you could see the videos that
exempli gratia, quae tu vides videos
that came out with that which are not
egressae sunt ex eo quod
accessible anywhere else but through
sed accessible huc atque illuc
twitter.com / Robbie Ferguson so and
twitter.com / Robbie et sic Tacitus
that's just us but I follow a lot of
quod suus 'iustus nobis sequor autem multum
people like I said and and it's
et dixi et populus amo illud
interesting to be able to keep up with
potest esse interesting ut cum
what's going on and it doesn't have to
quod suus 'iens in quod non habent
be a time commitment either that's the
sive sit tempus commitment ut '
neat thing about Twitter I think
tersus res circa Twitter puto
Facebook is a real time commitment if
Facebook temporis commitment est realis, si
you want to keep up with it but that has
sed id quod vos volo ut cum
been my concern it seems like a
iam enim mihi videtur de eo
commitment and what you started to
et quid vos coepi ad commitment
nurturing a group of people that you for
almum, qui pro grege hominum
sure yeah that's where I think twitter
yeah, ubi certe puto id egestas
also is pretty cool because you're
et est pulchellus frigus quia tu
limited to 140 characters because you
limitata ad characteres quod CXL
can so easily tweet from even a cell
ita etiam potest e cella tweet
phone like I have because you can so
et quia non potes me ut telephono
easily integrate it into other
Facile aliis integrare
applications such as the newsroom so
applications et sicut newsroom
that those tweets I don't even have to
tweets etiam ea quae non habent
send those their automatic things like
Eos in ipso sicut
that can happen okay that's really cool
fit, quod bene ut 'possit vere frigus
so twitter com is the the place to check
egestas ut sit loci com sisto
out and I know that a lot of you are
et scio quia tu es multum
already on Twitter probably following us
Twitter jam probabiliter post nos
like twitter.com / Robbie Ferguson I'm
sicut twitter.com / Robbie me Tacitus
probably following you but for those who
hoc autem verisimile non est, qui
have not used Twitter for those of you
Non uti Twitter pro ea vestrum
who aren't quite familiar with it we
qui satis nota sunt, non autem apud nos
want to walk through and Eric especially
et praecipue per Eric volunt ambulare
we want to get him signed up so it's a
nos volo impetro ut suus 'a se signati
really well laid out service and it's
bene de re officium et posuit illud
not too cluttered so you're just going
non cluttered et sic erant 'iustus iens
to click on
click to
sign up over here I was going to go
Suspendisse ut huc irem
through this full name Eric kid yeah all
per totum hoc plenum est nomen Eric hedum in frusta concerperet yeah
right there you go what do you want your
ius est ad ea quae tu vis tibi
name is you want try see if eric kid is
Si vis experiri Maecenas sit nomen hedum
available I think there's a computer guy
praesto puto illic 'a guy computatrum
who works at Nasr or something it was
qui operatur ad aliquid quod esset non Nasr
that name now let's try to checking
Sit nomen experiri coercendae
availability that username has already
quod est iam available nomen usoris
been taken so not fair what about one no
ita iam capta Non aequum est id quod non est de
no I wouldn't like that about each it'd
nolo nec quamlibet pergratum
know it's taken I call Eric robo-baby
robo-Eric sciat puer vocare suus 'sublatus sum
cuz it's it's a kid maybe Kid robo-baby
robo-cuz suus Kids maybe suus 'a hedum in frusta concerperet infantem
oh it's an inside Wow yeah okay well
utinam tam bene suus 'an intus Wow yeah
what could we go with you have a moniker
quid ad nos tu moniker
that you use I've had sfg quite often no
Ego uti satis frequenter non habebant quod sfg
I'm Matilda's probably taken what is it
Capta est verisimile quod ego Matilda est scriptor
sfg you got me on the small chair short
sfg vos got brevis me in parva sellam
fat guy no you're not liking that ok
pinguis guy non ok quod tibi non placet,
this is the joys of such a popular
hoc est epulae tantarum gaudia rerum a popular
services you've got to find a name that
tu officia surrexit ut in nomine illius
works for you but it's not already taken
iam non tantum facit eam
ok well let's keep hacking this I look
ok etiam expecto quod lets 'servo caesim
kid cookies just kid buy it so yeah
tantum crustula et yeah hedum in frusta concerperet hedum in frusta concerperet emas
let's try that that's taken
accipiatur quod lets explorare suus
well what Eric I Whitney there's a lot
tum quod ego Thomas illic 'multus Eric
of those over there with a que no for
Non enim ea que in illam
kid are you seriously okay you have your
gravissime hedum in frusta concerperet tu habes bene vobis
pom I haven't hotter on the cob okay
pom ego habeo bene calidior in MANNUS
well we can go with actually what we've
bene nos habemus ad ea quae sunt in actu operum
been fond of slagathor we are like that
slagathor esse cupidum rerum, quae non sunt tamquam
what its seriously been taken that's not
quæ capta sunt gravissime, quod non habet
fair hmm don't know for those in your
hmm aequum non est in eis
never seen them any other ideas well
nunquam se vidisse ullum alium bene ideas
this is this what you can think about
Hoc est quod possit cogitare de
both how a star eva days this is how you
quemadmodum et Eva dierum a stella est quam vobis
there's no way there's no way and then
Ibi suus illic 'nullo modo et nullum
when we're at it will register ek kaam
quando sumus non subcriptio eam ad ek Kaam
or something you had a chance not a
aut aliquid tibi de casu non habebant
chance okay okay well then we start
okay okay etiam casu tum incipere
getting into stuff like this and then
in materia et sic accipit
you start getting into stuff like this
talis materia satus questus es in
and that's like okay that's available
et ut suus 'okay ut' available
but do you really want that I'll book
sed vere non vis ut faciam tibi libri
cat5 Eric let's go to be kind of like
ut eamus in genere CAT5 Ericus
that
quod
does that work for you because this is
non opus est tibi quia hic est
kind of like this is your identity on
idem est in hoc genere
Twitter mm-hmm you want to go with
Demo-mm hmm Vis ire cum
something that that you're happy with I
quid est quod laetus es in me
should have thought about this before I
haec antequam haberetis cogitatione
got here huh yeah any suggestions for
hic obtinuit omnem suggestiones pro huh yeah
you sanitize kid no kid Eric hmm I think
sanitize hedum in frusta concerperet nihil puto tibi hedum in frusta concerperet Eric hmm
you ought to check sfg kid Eric is
Hircus autem Ericus compescere debetis sfg
available let's do that that's kind of
praesto est et facere id genus
cool it have in it you can say it like
sicut frigus est in ea possis dicere
it's a name kid Eric okay that works
Ericus nominis purus est opera haedo
okay password i'm just going to put in
Im 'iustus iens ut bene password in
something all my passwords and okay okay
quod passwords quod omnia okay okay
i'm going to put in the just something
Im 'iustus iens ad induendum aliquid in
and then we're going to change it okay
et sic erant 'iens mutare bene
i'm going to write it down you can
Im 'iens ut possis ea scribere
change that so that it's your own
mutare et suus tua
password of course Eric at category 5 TV
sane genus Eric V password in TV
all right and I guess we can leave that
Ego coniecto nos omnes recti, et relinquo quod
checked it looks good terms of service
cultus ex bono spectat comprimenda
you got I didn't actually read all that
et surrexit legere omnia quae ego non actually
you did okay because we're about to say
ut bene fecistis quod tu dicis
create my account want the inside scoop
propter me vis creare intus inclinatur
you probably don't want Twitter emails
probabiliter tu non vis Twitter emails
so I'm going to check that box at the
ita quod reprehendo arca archa Im 'iens ad
bottom oh can we listen to it I don't do
Solum possumus O audite hoc non faciunt
all here a set of words but then you
hic omnia verbis Statuto autem tibi erit
have to randomly hit yeah we were
quas passim ad ledo yeah essemus
talking about that a few weeks back its
ut pauca de retro
reCAPTCHA that we were taught that way
qui nos docuit reCAPTCHA sunt illuc
and it really did have some kind of
fecerunt autem et vere quidam quaedam
random words that neither one of us
Neque enim temere verba unus ex nobis
could understand the security and I said
et dixi in securitate posse intelligere,
but it was fun it was great fun
Suspendisse sed magna fun
so that's what we're talking about
ita ut 'quis erant' sermo super
see they're putting in some background
ipsi erant 'videre background de pugnaculis munitissimum
noise so it's not easily determined what
Quae vox ita suus facile determinari
the words are but every word you hear
sed in omni verbo auditis sermonibus
please type oh no you seriously can't
O vos typus gravissime placere non possunt
get back this is powered by recaptcha it
adepto is tergum quod sit powered by reCAPTCHA
is this is going to be a problem folks
hoc est forsit est iens ut esse folks
okay
bene
when this day maybe that could be one of
si forte posset una die
them oh thank you recapture all giving
O ea recapere omnibus gratias ago tibi dare
us the words again don't click on the
non iterum nos verba per click
speakers everybody that was fun are we
qui fuit loquentium omnes sumus amet
having fun yet oh you were Eric they're
sed habens fun O tu eras qui Eric
a good category 5e create the account
creare boni rationem 5e genus
there we go okay so you can follow the
et bene ire potes imitari
steps to this is going to walk you
huic gradus est ambulate ad vos
through finding your friends things like
omnia per amicos tamquam excogitato
that essentially now that you're on
qui nunc te super se
Twitter okay right you can type in here
Twitter vos can typus hic bene recta
who are you looking for I look Robby
quem quaeris expecto Robby
Robby Ferguson maybe there is there I am
Tacitus Robby maybe non est me
and I'll click on follow and so now
Sic faciam consequuntur click
whenever you go to twitter.com you're
quotiens tu es ut twitter.com
going to actually see all the stuff that
Ad ea cernere oculis omnem supellectilem
I have said so you see it's it's all me
Locutus sum vobis, ut videatur actum est mecum
right now because that's the only for
nunc quia ut 'tantum
sure it's all about YOU isn't it's all
certus omnia suus 'suus' circa omnes non TE
about me so that's the only person that
ita ut 'tantum homo est, quod de me
you're currently falling the following
tu currently sunt haec decidentes
but what happens is as you add more and
at verum quidem est quod te amplius: et adde
more people then your Twitter feed
et populum tuum ultra Twitter
becomes a mix of all different people
et aliud est commistum
okay right so you get like a really good
sic vos adepto ius est vere bonum, ut bene
assortment of people that you're
Vesalius, ut sis populus
following you can get into news sources
ut possis in sequentibus nuntium sources
i follow some technology news sources
sequor de technology nuntium sources
that i get tweets when they talk about
quae loqui cum ego adepto tweets
technology and things like that so it's
technology, et huiusmodi, sic suus '
very very cool so now that you've got an
ita nunc youve 'got valde frigidus est
account you're going to need an avatar
Quare erant 'iens ut postulo vestri avatar
you're going to need to be able to set
vos erant 'iens ut postulo ut possint
up an image for your user because right
ad imaginem jus tuis
now you're just going to look like a
Nunc erant 'iustus iens ut vultus amo a
little egg you don't necessarily want to
ovum non minus esse velis
claim so energy is everybody who's on
et industria suus 'dici, qui in omnibus est
Twitter right now and now you've already
Et nunc egestas nunc youve 'iam
got three followers if you could follow
si secum comites sequerentur
kid Eric kigd er I see then you'll have
tunc youll 'animadverto ut haedi Eric kigd er
Eric be following Eric so that's what
Eric in his ergo illud est quod Eric
your photo looks like right now it's
iam vultus amo suus 'photo
just
tantum
I have a plus sign in a green circle so
Ut plus mihi signum viridi
what we want to do is we want to
si vis esse quod vis ut faciam tibi
actually create a photo so I'm going to
ita Im 'iens creo a photo actually
bring up I've got a photo of you and I'm
Ego got a photo of adducere eum tecum ego sum,
going to put this into the GIMP GNU
ad hoc in GIMP GNU
image manipulation program this is
haec progressio est imago manipulation
available on Windows Linux Mac and with
in Fenestra Linux Mac cum praesto
this application we're going to get your
applicationem huius erant 'iens impetro vestri
Marquis your square Marquis holding your
Marchio vestra quadratum marchionem tenens tuum
left shift key and then our pardon me
Shift key ad me et sinistram nostri veniae
first click on the image and hold so I'm
Primus ego click imaginem tarn
like that right then holding my left
deinde ut ea dextera tenens sinistrae meae
shift key as I'm doing that that's going
amoveo key quod Im 'iens ut faciens ea
to give me a perfect square all right
quadratum recte dare
see because that's what we want for
vident enim quod id quod volunt
twitter with twitter you want it because
twitter cum Twitter vos volo, quod
it's such a small thumbnail you want to
tanta vis est lectulus thumbnail
get a pretty close shot of your face ok
a satis proxima offa vultus ok tuae
so here i am in the GIMP I've got a
ita hic per GIMP Ego sum possedi
square around your face going to
quadratum circuitu ad faciem
right-click and go image crop to
et ad ius-click in imaginem seges
selection and then that becomes your
deinde lectio vestra
avatar so I'm going to save that I've
nisi quia sic Im 'iens habeo avatar
right clicked and go file save as and
nisi quod rectum ac file coniuctionem pressisti et vade
i'll call this Eric jpg and save don't
Cuius non salvet evocabo jpg
we do web be well now I just needed a
et nos tela ut iustus opus est bene nunc
file right so now I'm going to go into
nunc iure file sic Im 'iens exire in
settings here i am back at twitter com
Hic occasus reversus sum ad twitter com
I've gun settings and I'm going to go
Quia commune aut inmundum et vado ad occasus gun
into profile
in profile
okay so we want to go right through the
volumus ut bene perlustrantes
setup so there you are you're a little
tu ibi es setup ut paulo
egg so we're going to browse for the
sic erant 'iens pro ovo browse
photo that we just created on the
ut sicut creata a photo
desktop called Eric jpg okay fill in
Paginae bene dictus Ericus exhaustus escritorio
your information if you if you have more
Si enim magis notitia si
if you want to earn the wire and things
orci ac mereri voluerit
like that and then save sending requests
missis deinde petit nisi ut
to twitter com it's just uploading that
twitter com ut suus 'iustus ut discas
file and remember that we've created a
et recordabor file quod weve creata est
file that's a perfect square because you
lima quod suus 'a perfecta quia quadratum
don't you don't want it to get skewed
nolo illud facio non alid sinistra ut
you don't want it to get squished or
non vis ad adepto an squished
stretched okay settings have been saved
occasus bene extentum salvati
its loading the image then there it is
et ibi est et imaginem ejus loading
there so that now you've got kind of a
ut iam non habes genus
face on Twitter so anytime you tweet
Twitter faciem tuam, ut te aliquando Tweet
your face is going to be next to it now
ad faciem nunc fore
to be really simple I'm going to go into
Im 'iens futurus vere simplex ut in
design and we're going to pick a design
consilium capere consilium iens
that you like so if you want something
quod tibi si vis est aliquid,
like this you just click and it will
sic vos iustus click et faciet
actually change your twitter profile to
actually tui quandoque egestas ut profile
one of these preset designs and of
Pellentesque et consilia horum
course you can customize that down the
Scilicet ut vos can mos quoque
road but for now let's go with that
sed cum iam viam eamus
looks good alright and then go to your
Licuit ergo et bonum vultus ad tua
profile and we'll be able to see I guess
et erit profile poterat videre Ego coniecto
maybe we need to save or something but
sed quid opus est nisi vel maybe
essentially that's all you need to do so
omne quod est per se et non opus est tibi
you go to Twitter next time you go to
ire iterum vadis Twitter
Twitter I'm going to click on home here
Im 'iens on Twitter click here in domum suam
twitter com you've got a chance to
twitter com te nacta oportunitate
what's happening say what's happening
Quod fieri dicunt quod suus 'suus' fieri
i'm working the category 5 TV news desk
Im 'opus desk Genus V TV News
there we go so your first tweet is
sic ut ibi sit amet Tweet
actually me typing but yeah there you go
tu enim me yeah, sed etiam typing
so now you see that you are actually
ita ut etiam nunc vides
participating in very well the list of
participating in a album of nimis
messages from Twitter good looking guys
bellus guys boni nuntii Demo
on the you know yeah you gotta hand it
Redditus est manus eius super scitis yeah
to them twitter.com slash kid Eric with
Thomas cum eis twitter.com VULNUS hedum
two DS and of course my own is at
Duo autem mea nimirum D.-S.
twitter.com slash Robbie Ferguson and
exacuere vade et twitter.com Robbie Tacitus
that will get you started on Twitter so
quod vos adepto coepi in tanta Twitter
make sure you follow both of us and
et planto certus vobis sequentes ambo
we'll have a conversation do I have to
ego pol illum faciemus et nos colloquium habere
come up with intelligent stuff to say no
cum dicere non intelligentes ascendit supellectilem
absolutely not but you should be really
sed absolute non sit realiter
witty and exciting because people like
sicut excitando quia puer ac populo
witty and exciting because that's really
quod suus 'vere excitando quia puer ac
the best you know that's the pay i
i ut 'stipendium optime nosti
squirted huggy tonight costa well stuff
squirted huggy etiam hac nocte, costa supellectilem
like chris a young saying twitter is
egestas dictum est Chris sicut puer
like a TV with a hundred and ninety
quasi gens centum nonaginta
million channels are you watching a
vos vigilo a million channels
channel that's all commercials i don't
channel commercials ut 'omnis non ego operor
think so talking about basically
ita cogitare de basically
unfollowing people who do nothing but
qui nihil nisi unfollowing
spam and I can understand that and the
Non possum enim intelligere et non spamma designata
tyrrhenian five thousand who says
Tyrrhenum quinque dicens
drinking a coke that's well that's the
et bibens Coke ut 'Bene ut'
opposite end of Twitter where you get
Twitter vos adepto in contrarium finem
your sitting there I'm sitting on the
tuum sedebat ibi sedebat super me
porch yeah skagit wisdom says I just got
yeah porch Skagit sapientia dicit ego iustus got
notified of an update to x marks with ya
certiorem autem ad an update x marcas per ya
what that's like receiving word from the
quod est Verbum, quod accepto tamquam ex
great beyond really Oh kind of
O vere grandia quaedam
interesting that you would get that mark
interesting est ut vos would adepto marcam
tyson wins the award for the most random
temere lacus maxime conciliat tyson
tweet this week on recent tweets
Hoc septimana tweets Tweet recentem
Neanderthals were compassionate and
Miserator, et Neanderthals sunt
caring you know what that's funny he
tu scis quod ne ipse autem exquiram iocularis
should mention that because i was
quid est quod dicam
listening to CBC radio on the way over
CBC audiebant super viam in radio
here and they said they may I looked a
et vidi et ecce ipsi dicunt
little bit rough but they were actually
paululum frenum aspera, sed etiam eius
pretty gentle beings I still wins most
Ego satis vobis oneri esse maxime vincit
random brilliant not random at all my
Non temere omnino temere lux mea
tweet this week the repair shop called
Tweet hoc septimana dicitur reparatione tabernam
to tell me that they can't get the
dic ad eos qui non potest
needed parts to fix our home theater
partibus opus esset ponere sedes ad theatrum
system planned obsolescence makes me
ratio cogitavit obsolescence me
indignant we started out that way
indignatus est autem ut incepit via
Twitter can be a lot of fun hey
Twitter potest esse multus of fun heus
everybody in the chat room this is
chat cubiculum quod est in omnibus
category five dot TV nice to see you and
genus TV eu ad te, et dat quinque,
we have some stuff to give away what do
ut aliquid auferat quid ad nos supellectilem
we got nanodots oh I want to play with
O nos got nanodots volo ludere
the nanodots I'm gonna put this right
Im 'agnus dei posuit in nanodots hoc ius
back under that loop oh no I will
quod utinam non essem sub autem reversus loop
pulling out of the bag there you go well
non peram in vos etiam effossis necavit
a match spongebob every building nano
Opifex parem SPONGEBOB tecta
ducks that's the bag that comes with it
anates, quae est cum eo est, quod lapides sacculi
but you can win this it's a game that
vincere potes; sed haec quia suus 'a ludus
you don't need anything like batteries
non opus est tibi aliquid simile gravida
for there's a super-powered magnets if
nam illic 'a super-Lorem Si magnes
you have small children or animals you
tibi animalia sive parvulis
don't want to have them laying around
inter eos pono nolo
but certainly lots of fun you enjoying
certe non es lots of fun enjoying
that em but this is great fun great fun
Suspendisse ut est sed magna amet em
really fun look Luke just wobble don't
vere fun vultus Evangelium secundum Lucam non solum TITUBO
roll them around make sure you check out
Lorem fac eas volvuntur
episode number 156 for your chance to
CLVI est numerus pro res forte
win and we're going to draw for a set of
et statuto iens orci hauri
these right now you're seriously just
haec dextra iam vos es iustus gravissime
not giving them away look I have a nice
aspice illos dederit mihi facis
straight line of glue see that oh where
O si videres gluten recta
is it on your kind of your kind of be on
in genere est in genere vestro
the camera there were Django looked I
vidi ibi diam Django
just randomly threw them at each other
Sicut misit passim invicem
watch this I'm gonna toss another one
Coronas cornonabit alius autem ego argumentum hoc Im 'agnus dei
into the mix this British picks it right
in Britannico hoc tollit ius misce
up there super super strong they are
Super superhabundat et confirmati sunt
incredibly stronger they like rare earth
admodum rara terra fortior similis
magnets or what are they yeah i don't
ne quid illi vel magnetes Yeah i
i'm not in a dino no that's right yeah
Im 'non a dino quod iustum est nulla yeah
that's that's the word that's this is
hoc est verbum, quod suus 'ut' haec
way cool way cool but you can actually
sed modo frigus modo potest esse frigus
make patterns and things make some cool
ut forma et res, ut alii frigus
stuff with them and they feel kind of
tali materia, et non sentiunt
neat to play with it look good I'm
tersus ludere cum illa bona quaerere Me
Adrian okay are we doing the drop we are
Fusce ut bene nobis sumus facere gutta in sumus
I see who wins this I named it better be
Melius est videre quod nominatur non est qui vincit
in there cuz I'm keeping these
cuz haec observatio est in me
good luck everybody we are drawing for
pro fortuna quisque trahentes
nanodots a nanobot put a dot you can
nanodots nanobot posuit in pactum A: inpacatum potes,
find out more about nanodots at cat five
inveniet procul et de nanodots quinque cattus
dot TV / nanodots illness go my lord d
dat TV / d dominus meus ad morbum nanodots
higgins peter man john peter man ja ja
higgins Petrus homo john Petrus homo ja ja
annids john's congratulations you're
john annids gratulationem te
gonna have to challenge me to a shootout
agnus dei ad challenge ad shootout
on the hockey rink to get these back oh
hi rursus ut venias in hockey rink
hey we got lots to give away so make
ita sortem dare obtinuit consectetur
sure you get your chance by a nice again
certus vos adepto a nice quod tibi forte iterum
watch that hey nice bracelet let's see
Nullam tincidunt armillam videamus custodia
what you got going on he's making
ut omnia quae hic aguntur
jewelry over here look at the potential
at hic per jewelry est potentiale
here no I could I could do an earring
hic non potui facere potui Inauris
maybe no I'm better not so once we get
maybe Im 'non magis olim non dabimus tibi
your nanodots jot you're going to have
nanodots vos erant 'iens ut libet vestrum
to put something together and show us
simul et ostende nobis quid ad induendum
what you've come up with you can really
quam tu non potes vere ascendit cum
do some neat stuff and there are some
et supellectilem ac notans sunt quidam
instructions that come with it and you
cum mandatis et qui
can also get on to youtube and or onto
et quoque adepto ut YouTube aut onto
their website cat5 TV / nanodots and
CAT5 eorum website TV / et nanodots
you'll be able to find out you'll be
youll 'reperio quod possit ex te fieri
able to actually watch some videos as
vigilo videos quod aliquid potest esse in actu,
well we are out of time for tonight
etiam hac nocte sumus de tempus
congratulations jot on not done playing
gratulatione ad iotam non amet
nanodots you can play you can stick
nanodots vos can ludere possis inhaero
around and play until you need to go to
et circuit ad ludere ire debes
skip baki great to see everybody will
Baki magnum erit omnibus skip to see
see you again next week hopefully John
deinde septimana videbunt hopefully vos Iohannes
will be feeling better we're thinking of
melior es Sententia, et hoc cogito
you man and we'll see you on Tuesday
nos te video vos hominis et Martis
night seven o'clock make sure you tell
nocte horam certam indicare
your friends category five dot TV and
genus amicorum TV et dat quinque,
look forward to having having some time
qui cum aliquandiu expectamus
but you know what you know what I didn't
sed quid nosti melius nosti quod non feci
tell everybody it's October fifth so 100
amen dico omnibus quinto Octobris sic suus 'C
kids birthday happy birthday Alexander
Alexander diem natalem diem natalem felicem haedos
Canada on that note have a great week
Canada, nota sunt illa magna sabbati